Guide to the Yale Collection of American Literature Letter Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- "L"
  - LOWELL FAMILY (Box 18, Folder 689)
    - ___. 2 ALS to Rev. J. B. Felt, Boston; [n. p.], 1841
    - ---. ALS to "My dear Sir," Elmwood, Cambridge, 1858 May 1
    - Lowell, Julia. ALS to George F. Babbitt, Chestnut Hill[,] [Boston], 1889 February 16
    - Lowell, A. C. ALS (final page) to Mr. Shaw, [n. p.], undated
  - LUCE, CLARE BOOTHE, 1903-1987 (Box 18, Folder 690)
    - ALS to Anne Morrow Lindbergh, [New York, N. Y.], 1948 April 9
      Removed from: Raoul Plus, Radiating Christ (London, 1936), the gift of
      Charles A. Lindbergh, 1955
  - LÜDERS, CHARLES HENRY, 1858-1891 (Box 18, Folder 691)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Philadelphia, 1887 May 3, 22
  - LUEDERS, EDWARD G., 1923- (Box 18, Folder 692)
    - Carl Van Vechten and the Twenties: Literature, Society and the Arts. Typescript of Ph.D. diss. at the University of New Mexico, 1951
      198 numbered leaves
- "M"
  - MABIE, HAMILTON WRIGHT, 1846-1916, 2 (Box 18, Folder 693-694)
    - TLS to Seymour Eaton, New York, N. Y., 1899 May 31
      Gift of the Rev. Kenneth W. Cameron,
    - ALS to Donald Grant Mitchell, New York, 1890 October 18
      Removed from: his My study fire, N. Y., 1890 (Gift of the Misses Mitchell, April. 1940)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, n. p., 1884 March 25
  - MCCORD, DAVID THOMPSON WATSON, 1897- (Box 18, Folder 695)
    - TLS to George Parmly Day, Cambridge, Mass., 1946 April 2
      With particular reference to his What Cheer
      Removed from: Mr. Day's copy of McCord's What Cheer (New York 1945)
      Gift of G. P. Day, March 17, 1959
  - MACCULLOCH, HUNTER, 1847-1905 (Box 18, Folder 696)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Philadelphia, Penn., 1886 October 19
      Removed from: his From Dawn to Dusk...Phila., 1887
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Brooklyn, N. Y., undated
      Removed from: his Robert Burns; an ode on the centenary of his death...Brooklyn, N. Y., c1896
  - MCCUTCHEON, JOHN T. (JOHN TINNEY), 1870-1949 (Box 18, Folder 697)
    - 2 ALS to Clara (Elizabeth) Laughlin, Chicago, Ill., 1904 August, undated
      The first letter has the original addressed envelope
    - ALS to Mr. Glover, [n. p.], undated
      Thanking him for tickets to Julius Caesar Philip D. Sang, 1955
  - MCGINLEY, PHYLLIS, 1905- (Box 18, Folder 698)
    - Public Journal: typewritten copy of poem
    - Public Journal: galley-proof, initialed by the author
  - MCINTOSH, MARIA J. (MARIA JANE), 1803-1878 (Box 18, Folder 699)
    - Destiny, AMS
      An essay
  - MACK, WILLIAM FORD (Box 18, Folder 700)
    - The Adventures of Kirkland Cublar, Detective, AMS
      181 leaf
      A series of eighteen short stories
      Gift of P. M. Neufeld, December. 2, 1960, in honor of Edward Levy
  - MACKALL, LAWTON, 1888- (Box 18, Folder 701)
    - TLS to Milton Garver, New York, N. Y., 1927 November 7
      Bequest of Milton Garver, August 1937
  - MACKAY, CHARLES, 1814-1889 (Box 18, Folder 702)
    - ALS to George P(ope) Morris, London, 1858 October 13
      From: Aldis Collection of Autographs
  - MACKAYE, PERCY, 1875-1956, 3 (Box 18, Folder 703-705)
    - 2 ALS, 1 ANS to Julia Ellsworth Ford, Oxford, Ohio; Bupaurd [?]; Windsor, Vt., 1914-1938
      Gift of Julia E. Ford, March 1951
    - ALS and TLS to Emily H(ardy) Hall, Windsor, Vermont, 1926 October, November
    - ANS to unknown correspondent, Cornish, N. H., 1922 July 24
      Received from: unknown source, 1945
    - TLS to H(erbert) B(ruce) Brougham, Windsor, Vt., 1916 July 28
      Concerning a new plan for the Public Ledger
  - MACKEY, FRANKLIN H. (FRANKLIN HUBBELL), 1843-1904 (Box 18, Folder 706)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, D. C., 1897 June 30
      Removed from: his Laus Infantium... Washington, [1897]
  - MACMECHAN, EDITH ("MRS. ARCHIBALD MACMECHAN") (Box 18, Folder 707)
    - ANS, written on calling card, to [Charles McLean Andrews?], [Halifax, N. S.], [1934 August]
      From the estate of Charles M. Andrews,
      1944
    - ALS to [Douglas Robert?] Andrews, Halifax, N. S., [1934] August 10
      Removed from: a copy of Archibald MacMechan's Late Harvest, Toronto [1934]
      From the estate of Charles M. Andrews, 1944
  - MACY, ARTHUR, 1842-1904 (Box 18, Folder 708)
    - A Poet's Lesson, AMS
      Signed and dated: Papyrus [Club, Boston], November. 4, 1893 Poem of 6 six-line stanzas
      Removed from: Macy's Poems, Boston, 1895
      Gift of Mrs. Charles Seymour, December 6, 1957
  - MCLANE, LUCY NEELY (Box 18, Folder 709)
    - AL signed Lucy, written in pencil to "the Hazens": Pacific Grove, Calif., undated
      Removed from: her Sea gleams, [n. p.]
      c1930. Is55.t1.M222
  - MCNEILL, LOUISE (Box 18, Folder 710)
    - Typewritten copies of 4 poems: Aubade to fear; First snow; Nazi woman's prayer; and Never the dawn
      Gift of Professor C. B. Tinker, November 1940
  - MAGEE, JOHN, 1922-1941 (Box 18, Folder 711)
    - High Flight: ms copy in the author's hand of his sonnet
      Gift of the Rev. and Mrs. John G.
      Magee, October 1942
  - MAGNA, EDITH (SCOTT) (Box 18, Folder 712)
    - ALS to Bernhardt Wall, Holyoke, Mass., 1939 June 26
      Removed from: her Collected Verse, Northampton, 1934
      Plain funds, December 1942
  - MAJOR, GEORGE MACDONALD (Box 18, Folder 713)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, 1899 August 31
  - MANDOLA, CAROL M. (Box 18, Folder 714)
    - ALS to August A. G. Wiggers, 1945 September 7
      [With pencilled draft of his reply]
      Removed from: her Folly street and selected poems. Dallas [1944]
      Iy.M311.944
      Shortridge bequest
  - MANGAN, SHERRY, 1904- (Box 18, Folder 715)
    - Makes: Maker: Makes, original ms copy of poem, signed by author
  - MANN, ARTHUR SITGREAVES, 1878- (Box 18, Folder 716)
    - Presentation inscription to Edmund Clarence Stedman, St. John's College, Shanghai, China
      Removed from: his Prince Ivo of Bohemia...New York, [c1906]
  - MANSFIELD, RICHARD, 1857-1907 (Box 18, Folder 717)
    - ALS to James Gibbons Huneker, [New York, N. Y.], Thursday, [1906]
  - MARBLE, ANNIE RUSSELL, 1864-1936 (Box 19, Folder 718)
    - ANS to Miss Mary A. Jordan, Worcester, Mass., 1928 October 10
      From the estate of Miss Jordan, 1941
    - TLS to Miss Jordan, Worcester, Mass., 1928 October 26
  - MARIN, JOHN, 1870-1953 (Box 19, Folder 719)
    - ALS to Mr. and Mrs. E. L(awrence) Sampter, Cliffside Park, N. J., 1945 April 8
  - MARKHAM, EDWIN, 1852-1940, 2 (Box 19, Folder 720-721)
    - Preparedness. Autograph ms poem signed and dated, West Brighton, N. Y., 1920 December
    - Markham, Anna Catherine (Murphy). ALS to George P(hilip) Hambrecht, West New Brighton, N. Y., 1932 August 15
      Written on behalf of Edwin Markham, enclosing an advertisement for his books and 2 advertisements for those of Virgil Markham
    - ALS to Andrew Keogh, Westerleigh Park, Staten Island, 1910 December 2
      1 page with envelope
    - ALS to George S. Lockwood, Brooklyn, N. Y., 1900 March 19
    - ALS to Miss Kate Van Wagener, West New Brighton, N. Y., 1906 March 16
  - MARLOWE, JULIA, 1865-1950 (Box 19, Folder 722)
    - ALS to Mrs. Reiber, Monte Carlo, 1924 November 20
      Enclosure: TLS from John Cunningham to Donald Oenslager, February. 26, 1955 concerning the Sothern letter. With
      ms note concerning Mrs. Reiber
      Gift of the Drama School, 1955
  - MARQUIS, DON, 1878-1937 (Box 19, Folder 723)
    - TLS to The Actors Theatre Inc. (New York), New York, N. Y., 1927 March 17
      Sending a copy of his play "Out of the Sea," for their consideration
  - MARSH, CAROLINE CRANE, 1816-1901 (Box 19, Folder 724)
    - Harper, firm, publishers, New York (1906, Harper and Brothers). TLS to Mrs. A. P. Sanford, New York, 1906 November 27
  - MARTIN, EDWARD SANDFORD, 1856-1939, 2 (Box 19, Folder 725-726)
    - We Who Sit Afar Off: original ms of his essay, written for Mrs. Wharton's Le Livre des Sans-Foyer (The Book of the Homeless), 1916
      Plain funds, 2 March 1940
    - ALS to Mrs. Maria F. Rand, New York, 1905 May 3
  - MARTIN, MARY, 1913- (Box 19, Folder 727)
    - ALS to Marian King, [n. p.], undated
  - MASON, GREGORY, b. 1889 (Box 19, Folder 728)
    - September Remember, by Eliot Taintor [Pseud.]. Typescript (original)
      1 leaf, 469 numbered leaves
      Written with Ruth Fitch Mason (joint author). Ms note on authorship signed by Mason on folder. Transferred from Mss and Archives, January. 1980
      Gift of Mr. Mason, April 6, 1958
  - MASON, HARRIET L. (HARRIET LAWRENCE), 1862- (Box 19, Folder 729)
    - TLS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Philadelphia, 1901 July 12
      (Removed from: her American literature, a laboratory method. Philadelphia, 1902 Za.M3814.901l)
  - MASTERS, EDGAR LEE, 1868-1950, 5 (Box 19, Folder 730-734)
    - Autobiographical Sketches. Autograph ms
      16 numbered leaves, mounted
    - Introduction to Chicago: original typewritten MS of article, published in "The American (M)ercury," with the author's autograph additions and corrections
      Plain funds, July 1945
    - Introduction to Chicago: printed proof-sheets, with MS corrections
    - How to Debunk Abraham Lincoln: typewritten MS with the author's autograph additions and corrections [Review written for "The American (M)ercury" of R. P. Basler's "The Lincoln legend"]
    - Late August. Typescript of poem with author's signature
    - Desolate Scythia: typescript of poem, with signature
    - Petit, the Poet. Typewritten copy (carbon). Poem from his "Spoon River Anthology." With ms note in hand of William Rose Benét
      Gift of Mrs. William Rose Benét, 1951
    - Hortense Robbins. Typewritten copy (carbon). Poem from his "Spoon River Anthology"
    - Lucinda Matlock. Typed copy (carbon). Poem from his "Spoon River Anthology." With ms notes in the hand of William Rose Benét
    - TLS and ANS to Mrs. George Pierce Baker, n. p., 1935 November-December
      [Mrs. Baker's MS note of explanation
      laid in]
    - TLS to Theo Feldmann [i.e. Feldman], New York, N. Y., 1937 November 18
      Gift of Mr. Feldman, December 1954
  - MATSON, CORA A. (Box 19, Folder 735)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Floridaville, N. Y., 1892 April 15
      Removed from: her As the Cardinal Flower...Fulton, N. Y., [1892]
  - MATTHEWS, BRANDER, 1852-1929, 3 (Box 19, Folder 736-738)
    - ALS to Henry Cuyler Bunner, New York, 1888 November 19
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," New York, N. Y., 1898 June 2
      Concerning addresses on E. 17 Street and books written there Removed from: Airs from Arcady and Elsewhere by H. C. Bunner, New York, 1884, etd. ed.
      Purchased from Van Nosdall April 25, 1958 from Kennedy fund
    - ALS to R. O. Williams, New York, 1897 May 16
      Removed from: his The American of the future...New York, 1909
    - ALS. New York, 1881 January 15
      2 pages mounted on sheet with portrait
    - ALS to F(red) H(olland) Day, New York, N. Y., 1889 January 23
    - ALS to [Erastus] Brainerd, New York, N. Y., 1883 April 22
    - ALS to Mr. Edwards, New York, N. Y., 1885 February 25
    - ALS to Mr. Harvier, New York, N. Y., 1879 December 9
    - ALS to William H(enry) Rideing, New York, N. Y., 1897 March 23
    - ALS to "Dear Russell," New York, N. Y., 1899 November 1
      Asking if he still wishes to publish "Peter Stuyvesant" in spite of its failure on the stage
    - ALS to "Dear Sears," New York, N. Y., 1899 December 6
    - ALS to Professor Wendell [?], New York, N. Y., 1899 May 12
    - ALS to Mr. Clarke, New York, N. Y., 1908 October 11
      Agreeing to say a few words "next Sunday evening"
    - ANS to John Kendrick Bangs, New York, N. Y., 1912 April 2
      Gift of Francis Hyde Bangs, March 1941
    - 2 ALS to Erastus Brainerd, New York, N. Y. and London, 1884, 1886
    - ANS to Leonard Charles van Hoppen, Narragansett Pier, R. I., 1898 August 10
      [Removed from: Za copy of his Tales of Fantasy and Fact, N.Y., 1896]
      Stanton F. Kennedy fund, 1939
    - ANS to James Gibbons Huneker, New York, N. Y., 1909 April 14
    - Autograph signature, dated, 1899 September 13
      Removed from: his Books and play-books...London, 1895
      From the Morse collection of Mark Twain
    - ALS to Mrs. Norma L. Munro, New York, N. Y., 1899 September 21
      Refusing an invitation to contribute to her new magazine
  - MEADE, JULIAN R. (JULIAN RUTHERFOORD), 1909-1940 (Box 19, Folder 739)
    - ALS to Miss Annie Burr Jennings, Danville, Virginia, 1936 December 28
      Removed from: a copy of his Adam's Profession, 1936
  - MELVILLE, HERMAN, 1819-1891, 6 (Box 20, Folder 740-745)
    - Hillway, Tyrus. Captain Ahab, a drama in four acts...Based on the novel, Moby Dick, by Herman Melville, [n. p.], undated
      1 leaf, iv numbered leaves, 1 leaf, 33 numbered leaves
    - ALS to E. C. Stedman, [New York], January 29
      1 page [bound in volume]
      Accompanied by photograph of Melville in 1885, a clipped signature, and a signature on a card; also newspaper
      clippings
    - ALS to his Uncle [Peter Gansevoort], New York, 1846 June 22
    - ALS to Dix and Edwards, Pittsfield, 1856 February 16
      [Removed from: Za copy of his Piazza tales (New York, 1856)]
    - ALS to Richard Bentley, Boston, 1849 April 3
      [Removed from: Za copy of his Mardi (New York, 1849) v. 1]
    - ANS, District Office, No. 4 N. R., 1867 October 31
      1 page [with reference to Mr. Henry
      L. Potter]
      [Removed from: Za copy of his Battle-pieces (New York, 1866)]
    - ALS to unidentified correspondent, New York, 1873 September 8
      Removed from: Za copy of his Moby Dick (New York, 1851)
    - ALS to Mrs. Ellen (Marett) Gifford, New York, N. Y., 1885 October 5
      4 pages with photograph of Herman Melville by Rockwood, New York, N. Y., 11 x 17 cm.
      From: the Simeon E. Baldwin collection
    - ALS to Leonard Sanford, New York, 1886 June 22
      Purchased, Alvord fund, July 1953
    - ALS to The Editors andc. [unidentified], New York, 1888 January 27
    - ALS to Lee and Shepard, New York, 1890 February 13
      Removed from: Za copy of his Clarel (New York, 1876) v. 1
    - 10 letters from Arthur Griffin Stedman, (Sir) John Murray IV, and the United States book company (publishers), to Messrs. G. P. Putnam's sons, regarding new editions of Herman Melville's Typee and Omoo in New York and London
      Gift of A. O. Vietor, November 1944
    - Suitor, John H. Social Criticism in the Novels of Herman Melville. Carbon copy of typescript of Master's thesis, University of Vermont, 1948
      4 leaves, i-iii, 1-120 p.
      Gift of John H. Suitor, 1949
  - MERCUR, ANNA HUBBARD (Box 20, Folder 746)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Buffalo, N. Y., 1893 April 30
      Gift of E. C. Stedman
  - MESSENGER, LILLIAN ROZELL, 1843-1921 (Box 20, Folder 747)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, [D. C.], 1886 June 28
      [Removed from: her The vision of gold. New York, 1886. Za.M563.886v]
  - MIFFLIN, GEORGE BROWN (Box 20, Folder 748)
    - Lloyd Mifflin, Notes by George Brown Mifflin. M.S. notebook on the life and works of Lloyd Mifflin
      41 numbered pages in copybook
      Gift of George Mifflin
  - MILLER, HENRY, 1891-, 4 (Box 20, Folder 749-752)
    - 8 ALS and 2 TLS to John Alexander Rolph, Big Sur, Cal., 1955-1958
      Purchased from: Rota, Alvord fund, 19 August 1960, along with other Miller items
    - Bibliography of Henry Miller's Works in Chronological Order, typescript (carbon)
      With annotations by the author
      [With envelope in which typescript was sent to J. Alexander Rolph, 14 September 1955]
    - The Colossus of Maroussi [Excerpts]. Typescript (carbon and original)
      40 leaves
      Contents. - Katsimbalis speaking, 16 numbered leaves - Saturn passacaglia, leaves 100-111 - Boogie woogie passa- caglia, leaves 139-149
      Each excerpt is inscribed by the author and is in the original envelope in which it was sent to Carl Van Vechten in August and Sept 1940. With the final excerpt is an ANS from the author to Mr. Van Vechten, dated 21 August 1940, 1 leaf
      1st section corresponds to Part I, p. 27-40, 69-75; 2d section to Part II, pp. [101]-112; 3d section to Part II, pp. 136-145 of the printed text (San Francisco, Colt press [1941]). 1st and 3d sections are carbons; 2d section is original
      Gift of Mr. Van Vechten
    - 2 ALS to Henri Peyre, Big Sur, California, 1945 March, April
      2 leaves with addressed envelopes and typewritten copies of the letters
      1 photograph with autograph note on back
      Gift of Henri Payre, 1951
    - TLS to Donald Goddard Wing, Big Sur, Cal., 1947 May 7
      Gift of D. G. Wing, May 1947
  - MILLER, MARION MILLS, 1864-1949 (Box 20, Folder 753)
    - ALS to Bolton Hall, New York, N. Y., 1915 January 2
  - MITCHELL, LANGDON ELWYN, 1862-1935 (Box 21, Folder 754)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Hawks Nest, Fayette county, West Virginia, 1887 October 21
      Removed from: Za copy of his Sylvian, N. Y., 1885
    - ALS and ANS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, N. Y., 1894, undated
      Removed from: Za copy of his Poems, Boston, 1894
  - MITCHELL, MARGARET, 1900-1949 (Box 21, Folder 755)
    - Brett, George Platt, 1858-. TLS to Helen McAfee (Yale Review), New York, 1936 May 25
      Concerning Margaret Mitchell's Gone With the Wind
      Removed from: Gone With the Wind, N. Y., 1936, by Margaret Mitchell
  - MITCHELL, S. WEIR (SILAS WEIR), 1829-1914, 5 (Box 21, Folder 756-760)
    - ALS to John S(haw) Billings, [n. p.], 1904 September 18
      Announcing the dedication to Billings of his The youth of Washington (1904)
      With an ALS from Billings to his wife, enclosing the above letter, and an inscription by Mrs. Billings. Also a reproduction of a portrait of Mitchell with an ANS from him presumably to Billings concerning it Removed from: Blum copy of his The Youth of Washington (1904)
    - LS to Dr. Corson [?], Philadelphia, Pa.
      Gift of R. F. Metzdorf, 1957
    - TLS to George Leon Varney, Philadelphia, Pa., 1909 April 10
      On choosing his favorite English
      poem
    - The Sea Gull, AMS, dated, 1898 November 24
      With ANS to "Dear Sir" sending the ms, 1 page
      Removed from: Aldis copy of his The cup of youth and other poems (1889)
      Gift of Owen F. Aldis, 1910
    - TLS to Miss Porter, Philadelphia, Pa.
    - ALS to Thomas R(aynesford) Lounsbury, Phila., [undated, 1906]
      Removed from: his Pearl...N. Y., 1906
    - ALS, Philadelphia, [1903] November 21
      Removed from: his Psalm of deaths... Cambridge, 1890
    - TLS to Dr. A. L. Loomis and Dr. W. G. Thompson, Philadelphia, 1894 February 12
      Received from: the estate of Dr. William Gilman Thompson, June 1928
    - ALS to Thomas Hutchinson, Philadelphia, [1903] February 3
      Removed from: his Masque...Cambridge, 1887
    - TLS to Katharine E. Hunt, Bar Harbor, Me.
      Plain funds, September 1944
  - MOELLER, PHILIP, 1880-1958, 2 (Box 21, Folder 761-762)
    - Wretched Woman, 2 typescripts
      126 leaves each
      3-act play
      Numbered copies 4 and 10
    - Wretched Woman, typescript
      125 leaves, missing title page
      Numbered copy 6
  - MOFFAT, DONALD (Box 21, Folder 763)
    - Maggie Bryan: typewritten [ms], together with galley-proofs
      19 pages; 9 pages
  - MONAHAN, MICHAEL, 1865-1933 (Box 21, Folder 764)
    - 2 ALS and 4 TLS to Mr. Manning, Mount Vernon, N. Y. [etc.], 1904-1908
      Letter of July 4, 1904 encloses ms copy of his verses beginning "O Albany! O Albany!"
  - MONROE, HARRIET, 1860-1936, 2 (Box 21, Folder 765-766)
    - ALS to Owen F. Aldis, Chicago, 1912 March 18
      Removed from: Za copy of her Dance of the Seasons, Chicago, 1911
      Gift of O. F. Aldis, 1912
    - ANS addressed to "Cousin Charles," Chicago, 1922 December 24
      Unknown source, April 1944
    - Minnewoc[?]: holograph ms, written on vellum, of a sonnet to Lenore [Nixon Bullen]
      Gift of George Kirgo, January 1953
      Preceded by a leaf presenting this and her "Dance of the Seasons" to Lenore Nixon Bullen, Chicago, Christmas, 1903
    - Dance of the Seasons: holograph ms written on vellum
      20 leaves
      Preceded by a leaf bearing presentation inscription to Lenore
      Nixon Bullen, Chicago, Christmas, 1903
  - MOODY, HELEN WATTERSON, 1860-1928 (Box 21, Folder 767)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Norwalk, Conn., 1903 September 12
      Removed from: her A child's letters to her husband, New York, 1903 Za.M775.903l
  - MOORE, CHARLES LEONARD, b. 1854 (Box 21, Folder 768)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Philadelphia, 1901 February 19
      Removed from: his Ghost of Rosalys, Philadelphia, 1900.Za.M779.900gb
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, West Philadelphia, 1890 April 9
      Removed from: his Poems, antique and modern, Philadelphia, 1883Za.M779.883p
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, West Philadelphia, 1890 May 23
      Removed from: his Book of day- dreams, Philadelphia, 1888
      Za.M779.888d
  - MOORE, L. BRUCE (LYCURGUS BRUCE) (Box 21, Folder 769)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Baltimore, 1897 October 17
      Removed from: his The death of Falstaff and other poems, Baltimore, 1897.
      Za.M7846.897f
  - MORGAN, ANGELA (Box 21, Folder 770)
    - TLS to Anna Hempstead Branch, Philadelphia, 1931 May 6
      Gift of the Library Associates, 1942
    - ANS to Anna Hempstead Branch, n. p., undated
  - MORRIS, GEORGE POPE, 1802-1864 (Box 21, Folder 771)
    - "Articles of agreement entered into on the 1st of July, 1836 between Geo. P. Morris and N. P. Willis," New York, 1836 June 23
      Written in the hand of Nathaniel Parker Willis (1806-1867)
      Removed from: his Loiterings of Travel...1840
    - ALS to Brantz Mayer, New York, 1858 May 18
      Removed from: his American melodies ... New York, 1841. Za.M8322.840mb
    - ALS to I. T. Fields, New York, 1856 January 9
      Removed from: his The little Frenchman and his water lots, with other sketches of the times. Philadelphia, 1839.Za.M8322.839l
    - ALS to Brantz Mayer, New York, 1858 December 7
      Removed from: his Songs and Ballads --, New York, 1844
    - ALS to Robert Bonner, New York, 1858 December 29
      Removed from: his The deserted bride; and other poems. New York, 1838
      Za.M8322.838
    - ALS to Coffin, Cold Spring, N. Y., 1860 May 14
      Includes Song, "Up the Hudson," Song and chorus, original ms Removed from: his Poems...New York, 1854
      Za.M8322.853pd
    - Noch Einmal Bin Ich Bei Sich Weider: ms of German translation of Morris's poem, I'm with you once again
      Removed from: his The deserted bride, and other productions. New York, 1853
      Za.M8322.853p.
    - To the Criticasters: MS of poem
      Removed from: his The deserted bride ...New York, 1843.
      Za.M8322.838b.
      copy 2
  - MORRIS, GOUVERNEUR, 1876-1953 (Box 21, Folder 772)
    - ALS to "Charlie," Westchester, N. Y., December 13
      Removed from: Za copy of his Yellow Men and Gold (1911)
  - MORRIS, HARRISON S. (HARRISON SMITH), 1856-1948 (Box 21, Folder 773)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Philadelphia, 1894 October 9, 25
      1 page, and 3 pages with addressed envelope
      Removed from: His Madonna... Philadelphia, 1894
  - MORTON, DAVID, 1886-1957 (Box 21, Folder 774)
    - ALS to Florence Griffith, Amherst, Mass., 1939 April 13
      Removed from: Za copy of his All in One Breath (1939)
  - MORTON, VICTORIA (Box 21, Folder 775)
    - TMS of a short story, The Enigma
      [Sent to Mrs. Powers from Catalogue Department, April, 1936]
  - MOSHER, THOMAS BIRD, 1852-1923 (Box 21, Folder 776)
    - ALS to Richard Hovey, Portland, Me.
      Purchased from Matthiessen funds, together with letters addressed to W. H. Wright
  - MOSS, FREDERIC (Box 21, Folder 777)
    - TLS to Henry W. Savage, Streator, Ill., 1904 September 3